Finding aid for the Ilmiyah collection of Arabic and Persian manuscripts, ca. 1516-1893 LSC.1654
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ilmiyah collection of Arabic and Persian manuscripts
circa 1516-1893
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1654
2.5 linear feet (5 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Collection consists of Persian and Arabic manuscripts about language and philosophy, as well as jurisprudence, religion, astronomy, medicine and philology.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Portions of collection unprocessed. Please see LSC's Access to Unprocessed Collections Policy for more information about levels of discovery and access of special collections materials and registering interest in unprocessed collections.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
9997007434906533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of Persian and Arabic manuscripts about language and philosophy, as well as jurisprudence, religion, astronomy, medicine and philology.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Manuscripts 1-3 (Box 1)
Manuscripts 4, 8-12 (Box 2)
Manuscript 5, withdrawn
Manuscripts 6-7 moved to Collection 1055, Shaykhi Collection of Arabic and Persian Manuscripts, manuscripts 40-41
Manuscripts 13-14 (Box 3)
Manuscripts 25-32, 34-38 (Box 4)
Manuscript 33, withdrawn
Manuscripts 39-42 (Box 5)
Manuscript 43 [oversize] (Box 6)
Separated Material
Manuscripts 6-7 moved to Collection 1055, Shaykhi Collection of Arabic and Persian Manuscripts, manuscripts 40-41.
Related Material
Persian and Arabic manuscripts in Special Collections Catalog Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Manuscripts.; Arab countries.
- The book of one who has never visited a jurist / The book of one who has never visited a jurist, 1585 July; Manuscript no. 1; 486 leaves: paper; 280 × 153 mm. bound to 281 × 158 mm. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Work of Shiite theology and jurisprudence, in five parts.
  Author: Ibn Babawayh, ?li ibn al-?usayn, d. 941
  Scribe: ?bd al-Ra?im Mazandarani
  Language: Text in Arabic
  Origin: Ottoman Mecca
  Layout: 21 lines of text per page.
  Script: Naskh.
  Binding: Bound in black leather with brown and burgundy leather paste-downs.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, headings and marked passages in red; double border in gold blue; some marginalia.
- The book of belief and unbelief from the book [called] al-kafi / Prayer book / The book of belief and unbelief from the book [called] al-kafi / Prayer book, 1700; Manuscript no. 2; 239 leaves: paper, ill.; 245 × 165 mm. bound to 257 × 166 mm. (Box 1)
  Two works of Shiite theology.
  Author: Kulayni, Mu?ammad ibn Y?qub, d. 941?
  Origin: ?afavid Persia
  Layout: 17 lines of text per page.
  Script: Nast?liq.
  Binding: Bound in faux red Morocco, stamped in gilt.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, headings in red; illuminations on 1b and 162b; few marginalia.
- [The light of the Sheikh of Tus] / [The light of the Sheikh of Tus], 1539; Manuscript no. 3; 305 leaves: paper; 213 × 140 mm. bound to 216 × 145 mm. (Box 1)
  Work of Shiite theology.
  Author: [?usi, Mu?ammad ibn al-?asan, 995-1067?]
  Layout: 8 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in red leather, stamped in gilt, with purple, green and blue marbled paste-downs.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, headings and marked passages in red; double borders in gold and blue; some marginalia.
- The laws and precepts of Islam / The laws and precepts of Islam, 1670 April; Manuscript no. 4; 334 leaves: paper; 285 × 189 mm. bound to 285 × 193 mm. (Box 2)
  Works of Shiite jurisprudence and theology.
  Author: Mu?aqqiq al-?illi, J? far ibn al-?asan, 1205 or 6-1277
  Scribe: Mu?min ibn Sayyid Iftikhar al-Lalih'abadi
  Origin: ?afavid Persia or Ottoman empire
  Binding: Bound in brown leather, blind-stamped, with leather fore-edge flap.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, headings and marked passages in red; double borders; marginalia; water damage.
- The jewel of desire / The jewel of desire, 1712 July; Manuscript no. 8; 192 leaves: paper; 287 × 188 mm. bound to 291 × 190 mm. (Box 2)
  Philosophy dedicated to Shah ?bbas II (r. 1642 to 1667).
  Author: Lahiji, ?bd al-Razzaq, 17th cent.
  Scribe: Mu?ammad ?usayn Tabrizi I?fahani
  Language: Text in Persian
  Binding: Bound in black leather, stamped in gilt; black canvas spine.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, chapter headings in red; marginalia.
- The source of faith / The source of faith, 1696 June; Manuscript no. 9; 167 leaves: paper; 162 × 89 mm. bound to 162 × 95 mm. (Box 2)
  Philosophy.
  Scribe: ?asan ibn Taj al-Din ?ul?an Mu?ammad.
  Origin: Ottoman empire
  Layout: 14 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in green and burgundy leather with marbled paste-downs; fore-edge flap.
- Delightful elegance commenting on the Alfiya / Delightful elegance commenting on the Alfiya, 1649; Manuscript no. 10; 172 leaves: paper; 162 × 89 mm. bound to 162 × 95 mm. (Box 2)
  Suyu?i's commentary on a work of poetics by Ibn Malik (d. 1274).
  Author: Suyu?i, 1445-1505
  Scribe: ?li Taqi al-Khurasani
  Layout: about 12 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in black leather, blind-stamped, with orange and green paste-downs.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, chapter headings in red; marginalia. Leaves [9-135] in different hands. Fore-edge title.
- Commentary on Ibn ?ijjah's rhetorical excellence / Commentary on Ibn ?ijjah's rhetorical excellence, 1684; Manuscript no. 11; 108 leaves: paper; 201 × 141 mm. bound to 202 × 145 mm. (Box 2)
  Four works, by three authors.
  Works 1 and 2 are by Suyu?i, [2-21] and [24a-80b], Shar? badi ? iyah Ibn ?ijjah and Shar? badi ? iyah ?a'isha, respectively
  3. Ba ? uniyah, ?a'ishah bint Yusuf, d. 1516 or 17, religious and secular poetry, [81a-98b]
  4. al-Maridini, Abu al-?asan ?li ibn al-Musharraf fl. 1442, Qasidah (hymn), [105a-108b].
  These works are seperated by one-page texts on various topics, such as a list of Ottoman emperors to Mehmed IV (r. 1648-87), on leaf [24a].
  Author: Suyu?i, 1445-1505 [et al.]
  Scribe: ?bd al-Qadir ibn A?mad ?azim
  Origin: Ottoman empire [Iraq]
  Layout: 19 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in soft brown leather with burgundy inlays; burgundy spine.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red; marginalia.
- [Commentary on the Ta?iyat of ibn al-Fari?] / [Commentary on the Ta?iyat of ibn al-Fari?], [16--]?; Manuscript no. 12; 96 leaves: paper; 180 × 117 mm. bound to 185 × 121 mm. (Box 2)
  Qay?ari's commentary on the works of Sufi poet Ibn al-Fari? (1181 or 2-1235).
  Author: Qay?ari, Dawud ibn Ma?mud, d. 1350 or 51
  Scribe: Mu?ammad ibn Abu Bakr
  Layout: 25 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in soft red leather.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red; marginalia. Title written on lower edge of text block.
- [Commentary upon the curative book in the science of conjugation] / [Commentary upon the curative book in the science of conjugation], [16--]?; Manuscript no. 13; 173 leaves: paper; 182 × 134 mm. bound to 192 × 140 mm. (Box 3)
  Commentary on the grammatical work of Ibn al-?ajib (1175-1249).
  Author: Jarbardi, Fakhr al-Din A?mad ibn al-?asan, d. 1345
  Scribe: ?usayn ibn ?li ibn Taj al-Din al-Najafi
  Layout: 18 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in brown leather with blind-stamped inlays.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, words marking quotations in red; marginalia. Author's name on bottom-edge.
- The adequate book commenting upon the complete book / The adequate book commenting upon the complete book, 1690 January; Manuscript no. 14; 153 leaves: paper; 245 × 137 mm. bound to 245 × 137 mm. (Box 3)
  Commentary on the grammatical work of Ibn al-?ajib (1175-1249), dedicated to a prince called Ibrahim ibn Yghrsh(?) Bilgä, the Khotanese king.
  Author: Astarabadi, ?asan ibn Mu?ammad, d. 1315
  Scribe: Mu?ammad Ism? il ibn Mir Mu?ammad al-?usayni
  Binding: Bound in brown leather, blind-stamped.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, underlining in red; marginalia. Cover title.
- [Anthology of religious prose and poetry] / [Anthology of religious prose and poetry], 1753; Manuscript no. 15; 97 leaves: paper; 203 × 129 mm. bound to 203 × 142 mm. (Box 3)
  Literary anthology containing the works of Shihab al-Din A?mad al-Suhrawardi, Mu?iy al-Din ibn al- ?rabi, Mu?ammad al-?amadani, Mu?ammad al-?a??ab, Badr al-Din al- ?adili, Abu Ishaq al-Asfarani, and Abu al-?asan Shadhili.
  Language: Text in Arabic, Persian, Turkish
  Binding: Bound in blue cloth over boards.
- The forty / The forty, [16--]?; Manuscript no. 16; 388 leaves: paper; 203 × 142 mm. bound to 200 × 140 mm. (Box 3)
  Shiite theology. An apologetic account, comprising 40 theses, of the ?lawite dynasty, paticularly of the twelve Imams in the light of various humanistic aspects.
  Author: [Qummi, Mu?ammad ?ahir, d. 1686 or 7]
  Origin: ?afavid Persia?
  Layout: 15 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in tan leather with blue, yellow and pink marbled paste-downs; black tooling on edges. Fore-edge flap.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red; marginalia. Leaves [1-38] possibly in author's hand.
- [Anthology of astronomy] / [Anthology of astronomy], [between 1795 and 1818?]; Manuscript no. 17; 167 leaves: paper; 157 × 108 mm. bound to 157 × 107 mm. (Box 3)
  Contains seven separate essays, in both verse and prose, on astronomy, including astrology, the science of astrolabes, and cosmic psychology.
  Language: Text in Persian and Arabic
  Origin: Qajar Iran
  Layout: Average 15 lines of text per page.
  Script: Naskh and Nast?liq.
  Binding: Bound in black leather, blind-stamped, with brown leather paste-downs.
- [Treatise] on the science of prosody / [Treatise] on the science of prosody, 1854 March; Manuscript no. 18; 46 leaves: paper; 176 × 109 mm. bound to 177 × 113 mm. (Box 3)
  Author: ?aba?aba?i, Mu?ammad Raf? ibn ?li A?ghar
  Layout: 12 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in soft red leather, with green paste-downs.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red; marginalia. Possibly signed by the author on leaf [1a].
- The pilgrim's gift / The pilgrim's gift, 1733; Manuscript no. 19; 284 leaves: paper; 197 × 129 mm. bound to 198 × 130 mm. (Box 3)
  Popular work on pilgrimage to Shiite holy sites.
  Author: Majlisi, Mu?ammad Baqir ibn Mu?ammad Taqi, 1627 or 8-ca. 1699
  Language: Text in Arabic and Persian
  Layout: 20 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in black leather, with red leather on spine and edges; blue, red and yellow marbled paste-downs.
- Exegesis of the [Koranic] chapter Iron / Exegesis of the [Koranic] chapter Iron, [18--]?; Manuscript no. 20; 108 leaves: paper; 197 × 129 mm. bound to 198 × 130 mm. (Box 3)
  Theology. Exegesis by the ?afavid philosopher ?dr al-Din Shirazi on the 57th chapter of the Koran.
  Author: ?adr al-Din Shirazi, Mu?ammad ibn Ibrahim, d. 1641
  Origin: Qajar Iran?
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red.
- Book of guidance for learning about the authority of God over [his] servants / Book of guidance for learning about the authority of God over [his] servants, 1654 June; Manuscript no. 21; 138 leaves: paper; 243 × 157 mm. bound to 247 × 168 mm. (Box 3)
  Work on the lives of Shiite Imams.
  Author: Mufid, Mu?ammad ibn Mu?ammad, d. 1022
  Layout: 22 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in brown and tan leather with green, blue and yellow marbled paste-downs.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red. Extensive marginalia. Title on spine and lower edge of text block. Insect damage.
- Blessed invocations / Blessed invocations, 1580 March; Manuscript no. 22; 162 leaves: paper; 166 × 108 mm. bound to 169 × 113 mm. (Box 3)
  Sayings attributed to the eighth Shiite Imam, with Persian commentary.
  Author: ?li al-Ri?a ibn Musá, d. 818 or 19
  Scribe: Khalil Allah Shirazi
  Layout: 10 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in soft black leather, with tan leather along edges and spine.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages and underlining in red; marginalia.
- [Treatise on dialectics] / [Treatise on dialectics], 1697; Manuscript no. 23; 83 leaves: paper; 186 × 111 mm. bound to 1889 × 117 mm. (Box 3)
  Two philosophical works, consisting of a treatise by Fakhr al-Din Mu?ammad ibn ?Umar Razi entitled Risalah fi ?ilm al-kalam [1a-50b], and marginalia by Khalifah Sultan entitled T?liqah fi ?ilm al-kalam [51b-83b]. The preliminary pages of the first tract are missing, though the author may be identified on leaves 4b and 6b, where his name is written between the lines.
  Author: Razi, Fakhr al-Din Mu?ammad ibn ?Umar, 1149 or 50-1210 / Khalifah Sultan (d. 1653)
  Scribe: Mu?ammad Karim
  Binding: Bound in soft red leather with tan leather spine.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red. Extensive marginalia on the first title. Title on lower edge of text block.
- Commentary on the [book called] U?ul al-kafi / Commentary on the [book called] U?ul al-kafi, 1665 May; Manuscript no. 24; 151 leaves: paper; 193 × 98 mm. bound to 193 × 102 mm. (Box 3)
  Shiite jurisprudence. Also known as The marginalia of our lord Mulla Khalil on the Preparation of the Fundamentals, by Mu?ammad ibn al- ?asan ?usi (995-1067).
  Author: Qazwini, Khalil ibn al-Ghazi, 1592 or 3-1678 or 9
  Scribe: Mu?ammad Na?ir ibn Af?al Beg
  Origin: ?afavid Persia or Ottoman Mecca?
  Binding: Bound in burgundy leather with green, pink and blue marbled paste-downs. Fore-edge flap.
- Mirror of truth / Mirror of truth, 1790 July; Manuscript no. 25; 180 leaves: paper; 205 × 118 mm. bound to 208 × 128 mm. (Box 4)
  Sufism, including anecdotes of holy men's lives, and verses from popular literature.
  Author: Maj?ub ?li Shah, Mu?ammad J?far, d. 1823 or 4
  Origin: Zand Iran
  Binding: Bound in soft red leather, blind-stamped.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages and underlining in red; some marginalia. Title on lower edge of text block.
- Treatise on the proper reading of the glorious Koran / Treatise on the proper reading of the glorious Koran, 1854 October; Manuscript no. 26; 68 leaves: paper; 153 × 101 mm. bound to 153 × 104 mm. (Box 4)
  Compilation of traditions on the proper reading of the Koran.
  Scribe: ?li ibn A?mad
  Layout: 11 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in black leather over stiff paper boards.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages and underlining in red. Water damage.
- Synopsis of the Quintessence / Synopsis of the Quintessence, 1654 February; Manuscript no. 27; 267 leaves: paper; 174 × 83 mm. bound to 174 × 88 mm. (Box 4)
  Arabic grammar.
  Author: Taftazani, Mas?ud ibn ?Umar, 1322-1389?
  Scribe: Abu Turab ibn Isma?il al-?usayni
  Binding: Bound in black and brown leather, with canvas spine.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages and underlining in red. Some marginalia.
- The solar tractate on logic / The solar tractate on logic, 1788; Manuscript no. 28; 187 leaves: paper; 206 × 104 mm. bound to 206 × 108 mm. (Box 4)
  Treatise on logic.
  Author: [Taftazani, Mas?ud ibn ?Umar, 1322-1389?]
  Binding: Bound in soft brown leather.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages and underlining in red; occasional charts and marginalia.
- Treatise on the Friday prayer / Treatise on the Friday prayer, 1716 June; Manuscript no. 29; 56 leaves: paper; 161 × 96 mm. bound to 161 × 98 mm. (Box 4)
  Religious text on the regulation of Friday prayers.
  Author: [Shahid al-Thani, Zayn al-Din ibn ?li, 1506-1559 ]
  Scribe: Mu?ammad Taqi
  Binding: Bound in multi-colored leather fragments.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, some underlining in red.
- [The treatise on the peculiarities of Friday] / [The treatise on the peculiarities of Friday], [before 1708?]; Manuscript no. 30; 8 leaves: paper; 212 × 139 mm. bound to 220 × 147 mm. (Box 4)
  Religious work in a fine, ornamental script enumerating the forty peculiarities of Friday.
  Binding: Bound in brown wrappers over boards.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages and underlining in red; extensive marginalia.
- Commentary on the summary of mathematics / Commentary on the summary of mathematics, 1635 February; Manuscript no. 31; 110 leaves: paper; 212 × 139 mm. bound to 220 × 147 mm. (Box 4)
  The author calls his work a commentary on the secondary problems of the text on mathematics by Baha al-Din Mu?ammad ibn ?usayn ?amili (1547-1621). Contains charts, tables, and drawings.
  Author: al-?aba?aba?i, Mu?ammad Ashraf b. ?abib Allah al-?asani al-?usayni
  Scribe: ?bd Allah ibn Khalifa
  Binding: Bound in orange-brown leather, blind stamped, with blue paste-downs.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink; extensive marginalia. Appendix on the last three leaves. Fore-edge title.
- The essence of the foundations / The essence of the foundations, 1638; Manuscript no. 32; 104 leaves: paper; 190 × 126 mm. bound to 192 × 131 mm. (Box 4)
  Shiite theology by the famous scholar, sometime vizier to Shah Abbas, the ?afavid monarch.
  Author: ?amili, Baha al-Din Mu?ammad ibn ?usayn, 1547-1621
  Scribe: ?bd al-Qadir ibn ?aydar
  Layout: 7 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in brown leather, with blue, yellow and white marbled paste-downs. Fore-edge flap.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, chapter headings in red; extensive marginalia; some stains and smearing.
- The book of the ?shariyah / The book of the ?shariyah, 1893; Manuscript no. 34; 132 leaves: paper; 190 × 126 mm. bound to 192 × 131 mm. (Box 4)
  Fourteen tales of the martyrdom of the third Shiite Imam, ?usayn.
  Author: Haj Shaykh J?far
  Scribe: [Illegible] Baqir
  Layout: 6 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in red leather, blind-stamped, with a brown leather spine.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; some marginalia.
- Pathway of the faithful / Pathway of the faithful, 1743 September; Manuscript no. 35; 136 leaves: paper; 211 × 125 mm. bound to 211 × 132 mm. (Box 4)
  Religious text on Sufism.
  Author: Ghazzali, 1058-1111
  Scribe: Shams al-Din
  Origin: Afshar Persia
  Layout: 16 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in brown leather, blind stamped.
- Tractate on Arabic lingustics / Tractate on Arabic lingustics, 1820 February; Manuscript no. 36; 116 leaves: paper; 207 × 147 mm. bound to 207 × 147 mm. (Box 4)
  Two works. The first work is Qatr al-nadá, [1-84]. The second work is entitled Mukhta?ari dar abyat-I shar?-I qatr, (Brief remarks on the verses of Shar?-I qatr), a commentary on the first text, by Ni?am al-Din A?mad al-Ardabili. Leaves [88b-116b] contain an Arabic grammar.
  Author: Ibn Hisham, ?bd Allah ibn Yusuf, 1309-1360 / Ni?am al-Din A?mad al-Ardabili
  Scribe: Afrasiyab ibn Malik al-?addad
  Binding: Bound in soft brown leather, blind-stamped.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in red; some water damage.
- Systematic account of the principal means of Shiism / Systematic account of the principal means of Shiism, [16--]?; Manuscript no. 37; 82 leaves: paper; 187 × 120 mm. bound to 197 × 122 mm. (Box 4)
  Shiite theology and jurisprudence.
  Author: ?urr al-?amili, Mu?ammad ibn al-?asan, 1624-1693
  Binding: Bound in soft brown leather, with green leather on edges.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages and some underlining in red; some marginalia.
- The book of important chapters about the fundamentals regarding the Imams / The book of important chapters about the fundamentals regarding the Imams, 1697; Manuscript no. 38; 300 leaves: paper; 180 × 116 mm. bound to 182 × 127 mm. (Box 4)
  Work of theology on Shiite Imams.
  Scribe: ?aj Khuda Bakhsh
  Origin: ?afavid Herat
  Binding: Bound in brown leather, blind-stamped, with orange leather on edges.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and some underlining in red; some marginalia.
- Part one of the book for the guidance of the community / Part one of the book for the guidance of the community, [16--]?; Manuscript no. 39; 214 leaves: paper; 223 × 160 mm. bound to 223 × 167 mm. (Box 5)
  Shiite religious jurisprudence for common practice; written by multiple scribes.
  Scribe: Mu?ammad ?alih ibn Mu?ammad J?far
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and some underlining in red; some marginalia. Occasional stains and ink smears. Title on lower fore-edge of text block.
- The book of the eminent selection / The book of the eminent selection, [after 1640?]; Manuscript no. 40; 116 leaves: paper; 182 × 115 mm. bound to 180 × 122 mm. (Box 4)
  Shiite jurisprudence concerning day-to-day issues.
  Author: Fay? al-Kashi, Mu?ammad ibn Murta?á, 1598 or 9-1680 or 81
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and some underlining in red; some marginalia. insect and water damage. Title on lower edge of text block.
- [Commentary on the wine poem of al-Fari??á] / [Commentary on the wine poem of al-Fari??á], 1626 August; Manuscript no. 41; 40 leaves: paper; 209 × 134 mm. bound to 210 × 135 mm. (Box 4)
  Jami's commentary on the Arabic poem of the Sufi poet Ibn al-Fari?.
  Author: Jami, 1414-1492
  Scribe: Asad Allah al-Ardalani
  Binding: Bound in brown leather, blind stamped, with red paste-downs.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words, original verses, and some underlining in red; some water damage.
- [The exhaustive one] / [The exhaustive one], 1648 December; Manuscript no. 42; 233 leaves: paper; 245 × 127 mm. bound to 247 × 135 mm. (Box 5)
  Taftazani's commentary on a work of Arabic rhetoric by Jalal al-Din Mu?ammad Qazwini.
  Scribe: al-I?fahani (mostly erased)
  Origin: ?afavid I?fahan
  Layout: 23 lines of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in brown leather, with black leather spine.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, underlining in red; extensive marginalia.
- Gardens of eternity / Gardens of eternity, 1713 [chronogram]; Manuscript no. 43; 35 leaves: paper; 415 × 255 mm. bound to 425 × 272 mm. (Box 6)
  Encyclopedic work of ?afavid times, dated by the chronogram of its title, which adds up to 1125 AH. Dedicated to Shah Sultan Husayn (1694- 1722), the work furnishes a survey of contemporary knowledge (religious, historical, geographical, medicinal, etc.).
  Author: Khatunabadi, Mu?ammad Ri?a ibn Mu?ammad Mu?min, fl. 1715.
  Layout: Average nine rows of text per page.
  Binding: Bound in black leather.
  Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words or passages in red and blue; text contained in silver, red, and blue borders; leaves on brown, blue, green, pink, and purple paper.